Northanger Abbey is a romance, drama, tv movie film directed by Jon Jones.
A young woman's penchant for sensational Gothic novels leads to
misunderstandings in the matters of the heart.
Catherine Morland, played by Felicity Jones.
Isabella Thorpe, played by Carey Mulligan.
Henry Tilney, played by JJ Feild.
Jane Austen (voice), played by Geraldine James.
Mrs Allen, played by Sylvestra Le Touzel.
Mr Allen, played by Desmond Barrit.
Northanger Abbey is a 2007 British television film adaptation
of Jane Austen's 1817 novel of the same name.
It was directed by British television director Jon Jones and
the screenplay was written by Andrew Davies.
Felicity Jones stars as the protagonist Catherine Morland and
JJ Feild plays her love interest Henry Tilney.
The story unfolds as the teenaged Catherine is invited to
Bath to accompany some family friends.
There she finds herself the object of Henry Tilney's and
John Thorpe's (William Beck) affections.
When she is asked to stay at Northanger Abbey, Catherine's youthful and naive imagination takes hold
and she begins to confuse real life with the Gothic romance of her favourite novels.
Northanger Abbey was one of three novels adapted for ITV's Jane Austen season.
It was shot on location in Ireland from late
August 2006 on a budget of £2 million.
The drama was co-produced by Granada Productions
and American studio WGBH Boston.
Northanger Abbey premiered on 25 March 2007 in the United
Kingdom and on 16 December 2007 in Canada.
It was broadcast in the United States and Australia in 2008.
The drama was viewed by 5.6 million people in the UK, making it
the second most watched of the 2007 adaptations.
Northanger Abbey garnered mostly positive reviews from television
critics, with many praising the cast's performances.
The tone is emotional.